[
    {
      "question": "Which statement defines oxidation?",
      "options": [
        "Gain of electron",
        "Gain of hydrogen",
        "Loss of oxygen",
        "Increase in oxidation number"
      ],
      "answer": "Increase in oxidation number"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an electrolyte?",
      "options": [
        "Glucose",
        "Naphthalene",
        "Sodium chloride solution",
        "Glacial ethanoic acid"
      ],
      "answer": "Sodium chloride solution"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following reactants is most suitable for the preparation of silver chloride?",
      "options": [
        "Silver and hydrochloric acid",
        "Aqueous silver nitrate and aqueous sodium chloride",
        "Aqueous silver nitrate and sodium hydroxide",
        "Solid silver carbonate and hydrochloric acid"
      ],
      "answer": "Aqueous silver nitrate and aqueous sodium chloride"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is correct in the electrolysis of molten lead (II) bromide?",
      "options": [
        "ANODE: Pb2+ + 2e → Pb ; CATHODE: 2Br− → Br2 + 2e",
        "ANODE: 2Br− → Br2 + 2e ; CATHODE: Pb2+ + 2e → Pb",
        "ANODE: Pb2+ → Pb + 2e ; CATHODE: 2Br− + 2e → Br2",
        "ANODE: 2Br− + 2e → Br2 ; CATHODE: Pb2+ → Pb + 2e"
      ],
      "answer": "ANODE: 2Br− → Br2 + 2e ; CATHODE: Pb2+ + 2e → Pb"
    },
    {
      "question": "A thermochemical equation is given as below: Zn + CuSO4 → ZnSO4 + Cu; ΔH = -210 kJ mol−1. What is the temperature increase if 50 cm³ of 0.2 mol dm−3 copper (II) sulphate solution is added with excess zinc? [c = 4.2 J g−1 °C−1 ; Density of solution = 1 g cm−3]",
      "options": ["0.01 °C", "10.5 °C", "10 °C", "200 °C"],
      "answer": "10 °C"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which factor does not affect the discharge of ions at electrodes during electrolysis of an aqueous solution?",
      "options": [
        "Position of ions in the electrochemical series",
        "Concentration of ions in the electrolyte",
        "Volume of electrolyte",
        "Types of electrodes"
      ],
      "answer": "Volume of electrolyte"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the electrolysis of magnesium sulphate solution (MgSO4) using carbon electrodes, what is formed at the anode?",
      "options": ["Hydrogen gas", "Oxygen gas", "Sulphur dioxide", "Magnesium"],
      "answer": "Oxygen gas"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which substance forms yellow precipitate when added to lead(II) nitrate solution?",
      "options": [
        "Sodium chloride",
        "Sodium carbonate",
        "Potassium iodide",
        "Potassium sulphate"
      ],
      "answer": "Potassium iodide"
    },
    {
      "question": "The following equation represents the neutralization reaction: HCl + NaOH → NaCl + H2O; ∆H = -57.3 kJ mol−1. Which statement is correct about the reaction?",
      "options": [
        "No heat is absorbed or released during bond breaking and bond formation",
        "The heat absorbed during bond breaking is equal to the heat released during bond formation",
        "The heat absorbed during bond breaking is more than the heat released during bond formation",
        "The heat absorbed during bond breaking is less than the heat released during bond formation"
      ],
      "answer": "The heat absorbed during bond breaking is less than the heat released during bond formation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following reagents can change iodide ion to iodine? (More than one answer)",
      "options": [
        "Bromine water",
        "Iron(II) sulphate solution",
        "Lead(II) nitrate solution",
        "Acidified potassium dichromate(VI) solution"
      ],
      "answer": ["Bromine water", "Acidified potassium dichromate(VI) solution"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The following equation represents a reaction between zinc metal and sulphuric acid: Zn + H2SO4 → Salt + hydrogen. What is the name of the salt and its solubility in water?",
      "options": [
        "Zinc sulphate, Soluble",
        "Zinc oxide, Insoluble",
        "Zinc oxide, Soluble",
        "Zinc sulphate, Insoluble"
      ],
      "answer": "Zinc sulphate, Soluble"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which processes involve the release of heat energy? (More than one answer)",
      "options": ["Condensation", "Melting", "Freezing", "Boiling"],
      "answer": ["Condensation", "Freezing"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A group of students is required to confirm the presence of chloride ion in solution P. What is the suitable reagent and expected observation in the test?",
      "options": [
        "Reagent: Dilute hydrochloric acid ; Observation: Gas released turns lime water chalky",
        "Reagent: Dilute nitric acid and silver nitrate solution ; Observation: White precipitate is formed",
        "Reagent: Dilute hydrochloric acid and barium chloride solution ; Observation: White precipitate is formed",
        "Reagent: Dilute sulphuric acid, iron(II) sulphate solution and concentrated sulphuric acid ; Observation: A brown ring is formed"
      ],
      "answer": "Reagent: Dilute nitric acid and silver nitrate solution ; Observation: White precipitate is formed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which salts are insoluble in water? (More than one answer)",
      "options": [
        "Silver nitrate",
        "Calcium sulphate",
        "Sodium carbonate",
        "Lead(II) chloride"
      ],
      "answer": ["Calcium sulphate", "Lead(II) chloride"]
    }
  ]
  